<bugreport schema_version="1.1" project="packetcraftr" version="0.2.0" subject_commit="6d967c729e1eb317271467fba3abeafa27445034">
  <metadata>
    <audit_date>2026-07-12</audit_date>
    <authority>This is the canonical, independently verified defect record for the audited revision. Supplied reviews are provenance; repository evidence and authoritative external contracts control where they differ.</authority>
    <input_reviews count="4" retained_issue_mapping_count="41" original_issue_mapping_count="42" availability="supplied-during-refinement-not-embedded">
      <review response="1" finding_count="11" retained_issue_mapping_count="10" method="static-source-review" />
      <review response="2" finding_count="8" retained_issue_mapping_count="9" method="static-source-review" />
      <review response="3" finding_count="8" retained_issue_mapping_count="8" method="static-source-review" />
      <review response="4" finding_count="14" retained_issue_mapping_count="14" method="static-source-review" />
    </input_reviews>
    <unique_issue_count>28</unique_issue_count>
    <merge_basis>Root-cause deduplication of the four supplied audit responses, followed by independent re-verification. Overlapping evidence, impacts, remediations, and locations were unioned. Distinct failure modes were retained separately. BR-012 was removed because the reader already enforces finite per-block and per-read metadata-count limits, its work is proportional to the supplied input, and the 256 MiB stream limit it was compared against is explicitly a captured-payload limit rather than a metadata budget.</merge_basis>
    <verification>
      <issue_status status="confirmed" count="0" />
      <issue_status status="fixed" count="28" />
      <audit_finding_status status="confirmed-at-subject-commit" count="28" />
      <unique_issue_disposition confirmed_without_material_correction="23" confirmed_with_material_correction="5" rejected="1" />
      <source_mapping_disposition retained_without_material_correction="34" retained_with_material_correction="7" rejected="1" />
      <location_count checked="70" missing="0" invalid_range="0" />
      <local_toolchain command="cargo test --locked --all-features" rustc="1.96.0 (ac68faa20 2026-05-25)" result="passed" tests_passed="337" tests_failed="0" date="2026-07-12" />
      <runtime_reproductions count="11">
        <reproduction issue="BR-008" result="confirmed">A temporary public-API integration check opened base sequence 100, submitted sequence 90 with five payload bytes and FIN, and observed a Closed event.</reproduction>
        <reproduction issue="BR-010" result="confirmed">A pre-epoch frame with a previously unseen link type returned TimestampOutOfRange after the PCAPNG output length had increased by one interface block.</reproduction>
        <reproduction issue="BR-013" result="confirmed">A new SYN with a different initial sequence on a retained four-tuple remained attached to the old generation and did not emit its contiguous payload.</reproduction>
        <reproduction issue="BR-016" result="confirmed">A public SystemRouteProvider lookup executed inside a current-thread Tokio runtime panicked at src/net/platform/linux.rs:153 with "Cannot start a runtime from within a runtime".</reproduction>
        <reproduction issue="BR-019" result="confirmed">Direct use of the public decoder on a syntactically complete BADVERS response with OPT extended RCODE 1 produced response_code 0 and response_code_name no_error.</reproduction>
        <reproduction issue="BR-020" result="confirmed">A response containing an answer-owner label with an embedded dot octet returned InvalidLabelData.</reproduction>
        <reproduction issue="BR-021" result="confirmed">Removing the inner IPv4 boundary changed an enclosing IPv4 total length by exactly the four padding bytes compared with preserving the shifted boundary.</reproduction>
        <reproduction issue="BR-022" result="confirmed">Two public custom layers with one shared ProtocolId and different schemas produced true in one structurally_eq direction and false in the other.</reproduction>
        <reproduction issue="BR-025" result="confirmed">target/debug/packetcraftr read -- --output=json extra exited with status 2 and emitted JSON, demonstrating post-terminator output-mode detection.</reproduction>
        <reproduction issue="BR-026" result="confirmed">FuzzRequest::validate rejected first_case=u64::MAX and cases=1 with CaseIndexOverflow.</reproduction>
        <reproduction issue="BR-027" result="confirmed">Duration::try_from_secs_f64 returned Ok(0ns) for positive inputs 4.9e-10, 1e-20, and 1/f64::MAX under Rust 1.96.0.</reproduction>
      </runtime_reproductions>
      <ci commit="6d967c729e1eb317271467fba3abeafa27445034" result="passed" reference="ci-run">
        <job name="linux-x86_64" conclusion="success" />
        <job name="windows-msvc" conclusion="success" />
        <job name="macos-x86_64" conclusion="success" />
        <job name="macos-arm64" conclusion="success" />
      </ci>
      <scope_note>Every retained issue mechanism was independently traced in the audited source. Eleven issues were additionally reproduced at runtime as listed above. Windows-native, macOS-native, and network-dependent impacts were not executed locally unless an issue says otherwise.</scope_note>
      <remediation_progress date="2026-07-12" base_commit="896e53cd40f7782474d1c3a10351bb4225d7206e" fixed="28" open="0">
        <fixed_issues>BR-001 BR-002 BR-003 BR-004 BR-005 BR-006 BR-007 BR-008 BR-009 BR-010 BR-011 BR-013 BR-014 BR-015 BR-016 BR-017 BR-018 BR-019 BR-020 BR-021 BR-022 BR-023 BR-024 BR-025 BR-026 BR-027 BR-028 BR-029</fixed_issues>
        <open_issues />
        <test command="cargo test --locked --all-features --lib" result="passed" tests_passed="279" tests_failed="0" />
        <test command="cargo test --locked --all-features" result="passed" tests_passed="363" tests_failed="0" />
        <test command="cargo test --locked --all-features --test cli parse_error_output_detection_respects_the_end_of_options_marker" result="passed" tests_passed="1" tests_failed="0" />
        <test command="cargo clippy --locked --all-targets --no-default-features -- -D warnings" target="x86_64-unknown-linux-gnu" result="passed" />
        <test command="cargo clippy --locked --all-targets -- -D warnings" target="x86_64-unknown-linux-gnu" result="passed" />
        <test command="cargo clippy --locked --all-targets --all-features -- -D warnings" target="x86_64-unknown-linux-gnu" result="passed" />
        <test command="cargo check --locked --all-targets --no-default-features" target="x86_64-unknown-linux-gnu" result="passed" />
        <test command="cargo check --locked --all-targets" target="x86_64-unknown-linux-gnu" result="passed" />
        <test command="cargo deny check" result="passed" />
        <test command="cargo check --locked --target x86_64-pc-windows-msvc" result="passed" />
        <test command="cargo check --locked --all-features --target x86_64-pc-windows-msvc" result="passed" />
        <test command="cargo check --locked --all-features --target x86_64-apple-darwin" result="passed" />
        <test command="cargo check --locked --all-features --target aarch64-apple-darwin" result="passed" />
      </remediation_progress>
    </verification>
    <severity_rubric baseline="supported-defaults-and-documented-safety-contracts">
      <level name="critical">Catastrophic compromise or loss broadly reachable through default operation without substantial preconditions.</level>
      <level name="high">A documented safety boundary bypass or memory-safety defect in a supported path, with material impact despite any stated platform or network precondition.</level>
      <level name="medium">Material correctness, integrity, or availability failure in supported use, or a safety defect requiring uncommon configuration or environmental preconditions.</level>
      <level name="low">A narrow edge case, non-default invariant failure, interoperability defect, or diagnostic/API-contract error with limited impact.</level>
      <level name="informational">A verified engineering-control gap without a demonstrated product defect or vulnerability.</level>
    </severity_rubric>
    <canonical_contract>
      <canonical_artifact>report.xml</canonical_artifact>
      <public_disclosure derived_from="report.xml">report.md</public_disclosure>
      <location_semantics>Source locations are anchored to subject_commit, not to later revisions.</location_semantics>
      <identifier_semantics>Stable BR identifiers are not renumbered when an unsupported issue is removed.</identifier_semantics>
    </canonical_contract>
    <deduplication_notes>
      <note>Sparse dense-range allocation and invalid SessionLimits were split because the former is an algorithmic preallocation defect and the latter is a configuration/serial-number invariant defect.</note>
      <note>Pre-send timestamp rejection and processing-time RTT inflation were retained separately because one drops frames during freshness filtering and the other mismeasures accepted frames and deadline eligibility.</note>
      <note>Late deadline creation and unbounded zero-time draining were merged because both arise from the absence of an absolute deadline covering readiness, draining, sending, and collection.</note>
      <note>The two macOS findings were retained separately: one miscasts getifaddrs ifa_data, while the other reads sa_family before validating that a route sockaddr contains its second byte.</note>
    </deduplication_notes>
    <references>
      <reference id="rfc791" title="RFC 791: Internet Protocol" url="https://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc791" />
      <reference id="rfc5771" title="RFC 5771: IANA Guidelines for IPv4 Multicast Address Assignments" url="https://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc5771" />
      <reference id="rfc4291" title="RFC 4291: IP Version 6 Addressing Architecture" url="https://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc4291" />
      <reference id="apple-getifaddrs" title="Apple getifaddrs(3) manual" url="https://developer.apple.com/library/archive/documentation/System/Conceptual/ManPages_iPhoneOS/man3/getifaddrs.3.html" />
      <reference id="tokio-runtime" title="Tokio Runtime documentation" url="https://docs.rs/tokio/latest/tokio/runtime/struct.Runtime.html" />
      <reference id="microsoft-adapters" title="Microsoft IP_ADAPTER_ADDRESSES documentation" url="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/win32/api/iptypes/ns-iptypes-ip_adapter_addresses_lh" />
      <reference id="microsoft-getbestroute2" title="Microsoft GetBestRoute2 documentation" url="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-hardware/drivers/network/getbestroute2" />
      <reference id="rfc6891" title="RFC 6891: Extension Mechanisms for DNS" url="https://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc6891" />
      <reference id="rfc1035" title="RFC 1035: Domain Names - Implementation and Specification" url="https://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc1035" />
      <reference id="rust-duration" title="Rust Duration floating-point conversion documentation" url="https://doc.rust-lang.org/std/time/struct.Duration.html#method.try_from_secs_f64" />
      <reference id="rustsec-2024-0436" title="RUSTSEC-2024-0436" url="https://rustsec.org/advisories/RUSTSEC-2024-0436.html" />
      <reference id="ci-run" title="GitHub Actions run 29157517928" url="https://github.com/tyk-swe/pcr/actions/runs/29157517928" />
    </references>
  </metadata>
  <severity_summary>
    <severity level="critical" count="0" />
    <severity level="high" count="3" />
    <severity level="medium" count="13" />
    <severity level="low" count="11" />
    <severity level="informational" count="1" />
  </severity_summary>
  <issues>
    <issue id="BR-001" status="fixed" severity="high" category="traffic-policy">
      <title>IPv4 LSRR/SSRR route addresses bypass destination authorization</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="1" finding="1" reported_severity="high" />
        <source response="3" finding="2" reported_severity="high" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/client/internal/policy_impl.rs:31-54</location>
        <location>src/client/internal/client.rs:70-90,149-163</location>
        <location>src/protocol/ip.rs:27-42,260-315,397-413</location>
        <location>src/workflow/replay/wire.rs:86-123</location>
        <location>src/workflow/replay/adapter.rs:46-57</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that typed live authorization inspects the IPv4 destination but not opaque option bytes, while replay separately extracts option types 131 and 137.</method>
        <reference ref="rfc791" />
        <precondition>End-to-end policy impact requires a network element that honors IPv4 source routing.</precondition>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>This bypasses the default live-target authorization boundary. The uncommon requirement that a network process source routing limits reachability but does not remove the policy defect.</severity_rationale>
      <description>TrafficPolicy authorizes fields named destination and IPv6 segments, but the built-in IPv4 layer accepts opaque option bytes. Loose Source and Record Route (type 131) and Strict Source and Record Route (type 137) can therefore carry additional route destinations that are never checked on the typed live-send path. The replay path already treats those embedded addresses as security-relevant, so live send and replay enforce different destination sets.</description>
      <impact>A packet can use an authorized private or otherwise non-public outer destination while embedding a globally routable source-route hop. On networks that process IPv4 source routing, this defeats allow_public_destinations=false before route selection and I/O.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Use one shared, fail-closed wire-destination extractor for typed live send and replay.</step>
        <step>Parse LSRR and SSRR before route-provider invocation and authorize every embedded IPv4 address.</step>
        <step>Reject malformed source-route options and reject unsupported route-affecting options rather than treating them as opaque.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Build an IPv4 packet with a private outer destination and a public LSRR or SSRR hop; assert authorization fails.</test>
        <test>Assert the route provider and transmission provider are not called after the policy rejection.</test>
        <test>Cover malformed length, pointer, and truncated-address encodings.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-002" status="fixed" severity="high" category="traffic-policy">
      <title>Globally scoped multicast bypasses the public-destination restriction</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="1" finding="2" reported_severity="high" />
        <source response="3" finding="1" reported_severity="high" />
        <source response="4" finding="PC-01" reported_severity="medium" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/client/internal/helpers.rs:362-380</location>
        <location>src/client/internal/policy.rs:16-25</location>
        <location>src/client/internal/policy_impl.rs:14-19</location>
        <location>src/net/route/planner.rs:287-303,691-709</location>
        <location>src/cli/arguments.rs:639-665</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that is_public excludes all multicast and that route planning directly accepts multicast and derives its Ethernet destination.</method>
        <reference ref="rfc5771" />
        <reference ref="rfc4291" />
        <precondition>Delivery beyond the local link depends on multicast routing and the selected multicast scope.</precondition>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>This directly bypasses the default globally-routable-destination opt-in and reaches the supported transmission path.</severity_rationale>
      <description>The public-address classifier returns non-public for every IPv4 and IPv6 multicast address. Multicast is not uniformly local: IPv6 scope 0xE is global, and IPv4 includes multicast allocations beyond link-local control and administratively scoped ranges. The route planner accepts multicast directly and synthesizes the Ethernet multicast MAC, so the policy classification leads to actual transmission.</description>
      <impact>Destinations such as 232.1.2.3 and ff0e::1234 can be sent without the CLI opt-in described for globally routable destinations. Active traffic may leave local or private scope under the default policy.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Replace the boolean public classifier with an explicit destination-scope classification.</step>
        <step>Classify IPv4 multicast by range and IPv6 multicast by the scope nibble.</step>
        <step>Safest default: reject multicast unless separately authorized. A narrower policy may permit only explicitly documented interface-local, link-local, or local-control ranges.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Reject globally scoped IPv4 and IPv6 multicast with allow_public_destinations=false.</test>
        <test>Verify any intentionally permitted local multicast scopes remain allowed.</test>
        <test>Assert rejection occurs before route planning or packet transmission.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-003" status="fixed" severity="high" category="unsafe-platform-ffi">
      <title>macOS casts ifa_data to libc::if_data before validating the address family</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="2" finding="1" reported_severity="high" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/net/platform/macos.rs:65-100</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that ifa_data is cast and dereferenced before the AF_LINK family check.</method>
        <reference ref="apple-getifaddrs" />
        <precondition>The unsafe read requires a non-AF_LINK entry with non-null, differently typed ifa_data on macOS.</precondition>
        <limitation>The platform-native failure was not reproduced locally.</limitation>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>A wrong-type reference and field read cross an unsafe FFI boundary in a supported platform path and can corrupt interface metadata or invoke undefined behavior.</severity_rationale>
      <description>The getifaddrs loop casts every non-null ifa_data pointer to libc::if_data and reads ifi_mtu before checking whether the corresponding sockaddr is AF_LINK. On Darwin, AF_LINK entries use struct if_data, while other address-family entries may expose a different ifa_data layout. Constructing a Rust reference to the wrong C object type can also cross the FFI boundary unsafely.</description>
      <impact>IPv4 or IPv6 entries can overwrite a correct interface MTU with a nonsensical value. The typed reference may read fields at invalid offsets or beyond the actual object extent, so the defect is potentially undefined behavior rather than only a bad conversion.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Read and validate ifa_addr and sa_family first.</step>
        <step>Interpret ifa_data as libc::if_data only for AF_LINK and only when the pointer is non-null.</step>
        <step>Prefer converting raw ifaddrs entries into a safe intermediate representation at one audited boundary.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Add a macOS integration test that repeatedly enumerates interfaces and verifies stable, plausible MTUs.</test>
        <test>Add synthetic tests for AF_LINK and non-AF_LINK entries with different ifa_data layouts.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-004" status="fixed" severity="medium" category="protocol-correlation">
      <title>TCP traceroute replies can be destructively assigned to the wrong probe</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="2" finding="3" reported_severity="medium-high" />
        <source response="3" finding="3" reported_severity="high" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/protocol/matcher.rs:19-60</location>
        <location>src/protocol/builtin_impl.rs:82</location>
        <location>src/client/internal/exchange.rs:175-230</location>
        <location>src/workflow/traceroute/engine.rs:162-203,246-303,425-466</location>
        <location>src/workflow/probe.rs:67-97</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that same-tuple probes tie in the generic matcher, are committed by request order and response count, and are only sequence-validated after destructive assignment.</method>
        <precondition>Multiple outstanding TCP probes must share addresses and ports, with direct replies arriving in an order that disagrees with assignment order.</precondition>
        <limitation>The correlation sequence was not exercised against a live TCP target.</limitation>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>This is a deterministic supported-workflow correctness failure, but it does not itself cross the tool's live-target authorization boundary.</severity_rationale>
      <description>TCP traceroute sends multiple probes with the same IP addresses and ports; sequence number is the principal per-probe transport identity. ReverseTupleMatcher uses only the reversed addresses and ports, so a SYN/ACK tuple-matches every outstanding same-tuple probe. The exchange accumulator commits the frame to one request using response count and request order. Workflow-specific ACK validation happens only afterward, and a rejected frame is not reconsidered for the probe it actually acknowledges. The same weakness allows overly broad acceptance of reversed-tuple RST traffic.</description>
      <impact>Valid replies arriving in arbitrary or reverse order can all be consumed by the wrong requests and then discarded, producing deterministic false timeouts. Spoofed or unrelated RST traffic can also be treated as stronger evidence than the TCP state permits.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Add a TCP-specific matcher that uses flags, request sequence, and response acknowledgment.</step>
        <step>For SYN/ACK, require ack == request_sequence.wrapping_add(1). Validate ACK-bearing RST similarly and apply SYN-SENT sequence acceptability rules to non-ACK RST.</step>
        <step>Do not destructively assign a frame when multiple requests share the same top confidence; retain all top candidates or invoke workflow-specific classification before commitment.</step>
        <step>Using a unique source port per probe is an additional practical discriminator.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Send at least three same-tuple SYN probes and deliver direct replies in reverse and arbitrary order.</test>
        <test>Verify every reply is attached to the sequence-corresponding request.</test>
        <test>Cover valid and invalid ACK-bearing and non-ACK RST responses.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-005" status="fixed" severity="medium" category="timing-correlation">
      <title>Valid immediate captures can be rejected as pre-send because timestamp precision and clocks differ</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="3" finding="4" reported_severity="high" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/client/internal/client.rs:306-342</location>
        <location>src/net/platform/pcap_backend.rs:83-115</location>
        <location>src/net/platform/live_capture.rs:499-518</location>
        <location>src/client/internal/exchange.rs:175-179</location>
        <location>src/workflow/dns/engine.rs:339-351</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed the exact comparison between a nanosecond SystemTime send marker and capture timestamps that may be reconstructed only to microseconds.</method>
        <precondition>The response must arrive within the capture clock's truncation interval, or the clocks must otherwise disagree.</precondition>
        <limitation>No native capture backend was instrumented to reproduce the timestamp race.</limitation>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>The defect can discard valid responses in supported local and loopback workflows, but requires a narrow timing or clock-source condition.</severity_rationale>
      <description>The send marker is recorded with SystemTime::now(), while native capture timestamps may be reconstructed at microsecond precision. Exact comparison rejects any frame whose capture timestamp is less than the nanosecond-resolution send marker. A response that arrives later within the same microsecond can be truncated to an apparently earlier time. Clock adjustment or backend timestamp sources that are not perfectly synchronized create the same class of error.</description>
      <impact>Very fast loopback, local DNS, TCP reset, and same-host responses can be discarded as pre-send even though they arrived after transmission.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Carry a monotonic receive Instant with every captured frame and compare it with the monotonic send Instant.</step>
        <step>Keep the wall-clock capture timestamp only as evidence metadata, not as an exact freshness gate.</step>
        <step>Where a backend cannot provide monotonic ingress time, define and apply an explicit precision tolerance rather than an exact cross-clock ordering test.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Use a send marker and later capture that truncate to the same microsecond; assert the frame is accepted.</test>
        <test>Cover wall-clock movement independently from monotonic time.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-006" status="fixed" severity="medium" category="timing-latency">
      <title>Response latency and timeout eligibility are measured at processing time instead of receive time</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="2" finding="6" reported_severity="medium" />
        <source response="3" finding="5" reported_severity="high" />
        <source response="4" finding="PC-06" reported_severity="medium" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/client/internal/client.rs:306-307,364-390</location>
        <location>src/net/platform/live_capture.rs:122-157,392-440</location>
        <location>src/client/internal/exchange.rs:134-145,203-230</location>
        <location>src/workflow/dns/engine.rs:170-174,413-435</location>
        <location>src/workflow/traceroute/engine.rs:468-472</location>
        <location>src/workflow/scan/engine.rs:484-488</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that latency is calculated with sent_at.elapsed() during consumer processing and that DNS compares that value with its timeout.</method>
        <precondition>Material inflation or rejection requires capture queue, scheduling, decoding, or matching delay.</precondition>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>This materially corrupts timing evidence and can reject on-time responses under load, but does not bypass traffic authorization.</severity_rationale>
      <description>The client stores a monotonic Instant immediately before invoking the send provider but calculates latency later with sent_at.elapsed() when a queued frame is decoded and matched. The result includes send-provider time, capture backend queueing, scheduling, decoding, matching, and accumulator work. The existing capture timestamp is not used for the primary RTT value.</description>
      <impact>Reported RTT is inflated under backlog. More seriously, DNS can reject a response that was captured before its deadline but processed after the configured timeout; a busy queue may also hide an on-time frame until collection stops.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Extend the captured-frame envelope with a monotonic received_at Instant recorded at backend dequeue or ingress, before decoding.</step>
        <step>Compute protocol RTT with received_at.saturating_duration_since(sent_at).</step>
        <step>Use received_at for timeout eligibility and maintain separate wire/capture latency and processing latency fields when both are useful.</step>
        <step>Do not derive deadline decisions from SystemTime because it can move.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Capture a response inside the deadline, deliberately delay consumer processing, and verify it remains valid with the original RTT.</test>
        <test>Verify processing delay is exposed separately if reported.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-007" status="fixed" severity="medium" category="resource-exhaustion">
      <title>Sparse fragment and TCP ranges trigger dense scratch allocation before quota rejection</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="1" finding="4" reported_severity="medium-high" />
        <source response="2" finding="2" reported_severity="high when limits are caller-controlled" />
        <source response="4" finding="PC-08" reported_severity="medium" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/session/fragment.rs:131-145,188-224,332-387</location>
        <location>src/session/tcp.rs:214-258,357-377,536-600</location>
        <location>src/session/mod.rs:13-41</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed dense span allocation and scanning in both merge paths before aggregate quota rejection.</method>
        <precondition>Default per-flow span is 1 MiB; near-gigabyte allocation requires a caller to construct substantially larger public limits.</precondition>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>The algorithm violates the documented finite-limit safety model and amplifies work under defaults, while the most severe memory impact requires non-default limits.</severity_rationale>
      <description>Both reassemblers materialize dense bytes and presence arrays spanning sparse logical offset ranges, then rescan and rebuild the interval map. Aggregate-byte validation occurs after this scratch materialization. Tiny ranges separated by a large gap therefore cause allocation and copying proportional to the span rather than retained bytes. A zero-length fragment at a high offset can consume work while retaining no payload and still increment fragment count. Temporary allocation and scanned span are not charged to the aggregate budget.</description>
      <impact>Default per-flow limits reduce the default span, but caller-controlled limits can permit near-gigabyte scratch allocation for only a few retained bytes before an AggregateByteLimit error is returned. Repeated sparse inserts also create CPU amplification and full-window copying.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Replace dense reconstruction with interval-native BTreeMap splicing over overlapping or adjacent ranges.</step>
        <step>Precompute conservative resulting span, retained-byte charge, and work charge before allocation.</step>
        <step>Reject zero-length IP fragments unless a deliberately supported semantic case exists.</step>
        <step>Add explicit maximum span/gap or operation-work budgets and account for temporary work separately from retained state.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Verify quota rejection occurs before allocation for tiny ranges separated by a very large offset.</test>
        <test>Add adversarial sparse-offset tests and benchmarks for both fragment and TCP paths.</test>
        <test>Cover repeated zero-length and one-byte inserts near the configured maximum offset.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-008" status="fixed" severity="medium" category="tcp-reassembly">
      <title>A stale FIN entirely before the capture base can close an active TCP flow</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="1" finding="3" reported_severity="medium-high" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/session/tcp.rs:174-200,288-289,341-388,715-724</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed by tracing the documented base=100, sequence=90, payload-length=5 example through trimming, clamping, FIN offset calculation, and close detection.</method>
        <method type="runtime-reproduction">A public-API integration check for that sequence produced a Closed event.</method>
        <precondition>A stale FIN and all associated payload must precede the retained capture base.</precondition>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>This can split or truncate a supported TCP reassembly stream and corrupt higher-level evidence.</severity_rationale>
      <description>Pre-base payload is intentionally discarded, but the code clamps the segment offset to zero before deriving the FIN position. For base sequence 100, segment sequence 90, payload length 5, and FIN at sequence 95, the payload becomes empty and the computed fin_offset becomes zero. The flow then closes immediately because next_offset is already at least that value.</description>
      <reproduction>base=100, segment_seq=90, payload_len=5, FIN sequence=95; current logic derives absolute=-10, before_base=5, payload=empty, offset=0, fin_offset=0.</reproduction>
      <impact>An old retransmitted FIN can terminate an active reassembly generation. Later bytes may open a new flow, causing truncation, duplicate sessions, incorrect lifecycle events, or evasion of higher-level inspection.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Compute the absolute FIN sequence before clamping or trimming the payload interval.</step>
        <step>Classify a FIN strictly before the retained receive interval as old control information and ignore it.</step>
        <step>Keep FIN state tied to the same unwrapped sequence space as retained data.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Insert a fully pre-base payload plus FIN and assert that no Closed event is emitted.</test>
        <test>Cover FIN exactly at the base and FIN after partially trimmed payload.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-009" status="fixed" severity="medium" category="unsafe-platform-parsing">
      <title>macOS route sockaddr parsing reads sa_family before validating record length</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="4" finding="PC-04" reported_severity="medium" disposition="accepted-with-correction" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/net/platform/macos.rs:247-268</location>
        <location>src/net/platform/macos.rs:471-525</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that parse_route_addresses accepts a declared length of one and passes it to sockaddr_ip, which dereferences the second byte as sa_family before checking a family-specific size.</method>
        <source_correction>Darwin libc::sockaddr has byte alignment, route records are rounded to four-byte offsets, and family-specific reads already use read_unaligned. The supplied alignment claim is therefore rejected.</source_correction>
        <precondition>The macOS route socket must return a malformed one-byte sockaddr record.</precondition>
        <limitation>No path giving an untrusted process direct control over the kernel route response was established, and the platform-native failure was not reproduced locally.</limitation>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>This is a real out-of-bounds unsafe read, but it is platform-specific and the malformed input boundary is a kernel response rather than demonstrated attacker-controlled data.</severity_rationale>
      <description>Darwin sockaddr begins with sa_len followed by sa_family. The parser reads (*address).sa_family before requiring at least two bytes. Route-socket parsing can pass a one-byte record, so the family read is out of bounds.</description>
      <impact>A malformed macOS route response can trigger an invalid memory read at an unsafe FFI boundary, with outcomes ranging from incorrect parsing to undefined behavior. Adversarial reachability has not been established.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Make the parser accept a byte slice instead of a typed sockaddr pointer.</step>
        <step>Require at least two bytes before reading the family directly from the slice.</step>
        <step>After exact family-specific bounds checks, use read_unaligned for complete sockaddr_in or sockaddr_in6 values.</step>
        <step>Reject one-byte, truncated, and overflowed route-socket records before any typed access.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Test lengths 0 and 1 and minimally sized unknown families without reading beyond the supplied slice.</test>
        <test>Exercise complete IPv4 and IPv6 records through the same safe byte-slice boundary.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-010" status="fixed" severity="medium" category="capture-serialization">
      <title>A rejected PCAPNG frame can still mutate the output stream and interface table</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="1" finding="5" reported_severity="medium" disposition="accepted-with-correction" />
        <source response="2" finding="8" reported_severity="low" />
        <source response="3" finding="7" reported_severity="medium" disposition="accepted-with-correction" />
        <source response="4" finding="PC-09" reported_severity="medium" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/capture/pcap/writer.rs:307-380,383-385,505-540,568-607</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that an unseen link type commits an IDB before timestamp and EPB-size validation.</method>
        <method type="runtime-reproduction">A pre-epoch frame returned TimestampOutOfRange after increasing the output length by one IDB.</method>
        <source_correction>write_frame checks frame-count and stream-byte limits before select_interface. Those limits cannot produce this mutation. Snap-length validation is textually later, but it cannot fail for an auto-created interface because that interface uses the already-checked writer size limit as its snap length. All three are excluded from the canonical regression cases.</source_correction>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>A documented prevalidation contract is violated and failed writes observably change serialized output and retry state.</severity_rationale>
      <description>The PCAPNG frame path calls select_interface before completing timestamp and Enhanced Packet Block size validation. When no interface matches, select_interface calls add_interface, immediately emits an Interface Description Block, and updates writer state. A later validation error therefore occurs after externally visible commit. Frame-count and stream-byte limits are checked earlier in write_frame. Although snap-length validation appears after interface selection, it cannot fail for the auto-created interface because that interface's snap length is the writer size limit already applied to the frame.</description>
      <impact>For example, a pre-Unix-epoch frame on a fresh writer can return TimestampOutOfRange while leaving an IDB in the stream and consuming interface ID 0. A retry observes different state, and failures involving different previously unseen link types can shift later interface numbering or consume the interface limit. write_frame therefore violates its documented prevalidation contract.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Split interface resolution into non-mutating planning and commit phases.</step>
        <step>Validate prospective interface properties, timestamp representation, and block size before writing.</step>
        <step>Commit the optional IDB and EPB only after all non-I/O validation succeeds, or stage both blocks in a bounded temporary buffer.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Submit an invalid frame with a previously unseen link type and assert output bytes and interface count are unchanged.</test>
        <test>Cover timestamp and EPB-size failures for previously unseen link types.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-011" status="fixed" severity="low" category="capture-parsing-limits">
      <title>The documented per-section PCAPNG interface limit is enforced cumulatively</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="1" finding="6" reported_severity="medium" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/capture/pcap/models.rs:1-6,137-140</location>
        <location>src/capture/pcap/reader.rs:210-239,277-296</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that section rollover clears the current interface vector but IDB validation includes interface_base in the documented per-section limit.</method>
        <precondition>A valid PCAPNG file must use multiple sections whose individual interface counts are within the limit but whose cumulative count exceeds it.</precondition>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>This is a narrow multi-section interoperability and documentation-contract failure rather than an unsafe acceptance path.</severity_rationale>
      <description>A new section advances interface_base by the previous section's interface count and clears the current section vector. IDB validation nevertheless checks interface_base plus interfaces.len() against the limit. The implementation therefore applies a global cumulative namespace limit while the constant and documentation describe a per-section limit.</description>
      <impact>A file containing, for example, 3000 interfaces and a packet in each of two sections exceeds the default 4096 interface limit even though neither section violates the documented constraint and each call remains below the independent metadata-block limit.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Use interfaces.len() for the current-section limit.</step>
        <step>Add a separate total-file interface limit for globally retained normalized metadata, or explicitly redefine and document the existing limit as cumulative.</step>
        <step>Align the error text and public API documentation with the chosen semantics.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Parse multiple sections with a packet in each section so every per-read metadata count remains in bounds while the sections are individually under the interface limit but cumulatively over it.</test>
        <test>Independently exercise any new global retained-interface limit.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-013" status="fixed" severity="medium" category="tcp-reassembly">
      <title>TCP reassembly conflates distinct connection incarnations that reuse a four-tuple</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="2" finding="4" reported_severity="medium" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/session/tcp.rs:19-25,131-139,161-170</location>
        <location>src/session/mod.rs:38-39</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that FlowKey contains only addresses and ports and that open_flow treats an existing key as success without validating the new initial sequence.</method>
        <method type="runtime-reproduction">A retained flow accepted a new SYN with a different initial sequence into the old generation and did not emit its otherwise-contiguous payload.</method>
        <precondition>A four-tuple must be reused before the previous generation expires or is otherwise removed.</precondition>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>This can materially corrupt or conflate supported TCP reassembly sessions during legitimate tuple reuse.</severity_rationale>
      <description>Flow identity contains only the address and port four-tuple. Opening an already present key returns success without checking or replacing the original initial sequence number. A new SYN that reuses the tuple before stale state expires is therefore unwrapped relative to the old connection generation.</description>
      <impact>New data can be classified as retransmission, conflicting overlap, a huge gap, data after an old FIN, or a prematurely completed stream. The default idle lifetime leaves a meaningful tuple-reuse window.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Model connection generation explicitly and track SYN, FIN, and RST lifecycle state.</step>
        <step>Replace stale or incompatible state when a non-retransmitted SYN introduces a new initial sequence.</step>
        <step>Keep retransmission of the original SYN idempotent and emit an observable replacement or eviction event when incomplete old state is discarded.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Reuse a tuple before idle expiration while incomplete state remains, including after an out-of-order FIN and when the prior close was not captured.</test>
        <test>Verify a completed contiguous FIN or RST removes state and permits ordinary tuple reuse.</test>
        <test>Verify retransmission of the original SYN does not create a new generation.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-014" status="fixed" severity="low" category="configuration-invariants">
      <title>Public SessionLimits can violate TCP serial-number half-space</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="2" finding="2 subfinding" reported_severity="not separately rated" disposition="accepted-with-correction" />
        <source response="4" finding="PC-07" reported_severity="medium" disposition="accepted-with-correction" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/session/mod.rs:19-41</location>
        <location>src/session/tcp.rs:121-129,174-184</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that sequence unwrapping casts a wrapping u32 delta to i32 while public Limits permits max_bytes_per_flow at or above 2^31.</method>
        <source_correction>Zero limits can intentionally disable capacity, and a per-flow limit above the aggregate limit can intentionally make the aggregate budget stricter. Neither relationship is inherently invalid, so both are removed from the defect.</source_correction>
        <precondition>A caller must replace the safe 1 MiB default with a TCP per-flow window at or above 2^31.</precondition>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>The protocol invariant is real, but the supported default is safely below the boundary and failure requires an extreme non-default public configuration.</severity_rationale>
      <description>TCP sequence unwrapping interprets a wrapping delta through signed 32-bit serial-number arithmetic, which requires an acceptable window smaller than 2^31. SessionLimits are publicly constructible with max_bytes_per_flow values at or above that boundary.</description>
      <impact>At or above the half-space boundary, sequence ordering becomes intrinsically ambiguous: the same wrapping sequence can be interpreted as before or after the base.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Introduce a fallible validated SessionLimits constructor or validate at every public entry point.</step>
        <step>Require TCP max_bytes_per_flow to be strictly less than 2^31.</step>
        <step>Document zero-capacity and aggregate-budget semantics independently rather than treating them as serial-number invariants.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Reject exactly 2^31 and larger TCP windows.</test>
        <test>Accept the largest representable value below 2^31 and retain documented zero and aggregate-budget behavior.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-015" status="fixed" severity="medium" category="deadline-control">
      <title>The overall response timeout does not bound sending or unbounded zero-time capture drains</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="3" finding="6" reported_severity="medium" />
        <source response="4" finding="PC-02" reported_severity="medium" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/client/internal/client.rs:281-390</location>
        <location>src/net/neighbor/provider.rs:233-261</location>
        <location>src/cli/arguments.rs:622-628</location>
        <location>src/workflow/scan/engine.rs:214-243</location>
        <location>src/workflow/traceroute/engine.rs:206-226</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that zero-time drains loop until None and the exchange deadline is created only after all sends and drains complete.</method>
        <precondition>Unbounded deferral requires sustained ingress or a backend that continuously returns frames; timeout inflation also occurs with slow sends.</precondition>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>The advertised overall window does not bound supported operations and sustained ingress can prevent forward progress.</severity_rationale>
      <description>Before and after each send, the client drains Duration::ZERO captures until the backend returns None. A bounded queue limits retained memory but does not guarantee emptiness under sustained ingress, so transmission can be deferred indefinitely. The exchange deadline is created only after every send completes. Slow send calls and pre/post-send drains are therefore outside the advertised response window; neighbor discovery has a similar unbounded pre-request drain before its attempt deadline.</description>
      <impact>The configured 'overall response window' is not a hard wall-clock limit. Early requests can receive much longer effective windows than later requests, workflow duration accounting can be exceeded, and sustained ingress can prevent progress altogether.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Establish an absolute operation deadline before capture readiness, draining, and the first send.</step>
        <step>Bound every zero-time drain by both frame count and elapsed time, carrying remaining duration through all phases.</step>
        <step>Alternatively define per-request deadlines as send_instant plus timeout and collect only until the latest deadline.</step>
        <step>If the intended API is a post-send drain interval, rename and document it and include send/drain time in workflow duration calculations.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Use a capture backend that always returns another zero-time frame and assert bounded progress or timeout.</test>
        <test>Inject delayed send calls and verify the total operation respects the configured wall-clock ceiling.</test>
        <test>Verify per-request acceptance windows are deterministic across request order.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-016" status="fixed" severity="medium" category="async-runtime">
      <title>Linux synchronous route lookup can panic when invoked inside a Tokio runtime</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="4" finding="PC-03" reported_severity="medium" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/net/platform/linux.rs:143-160</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed construction of a current-thread runtime followed by Runtime::block_on in the synchronous Linux route path.</method>
        <method type="runtime-reproduction">Calling the public SystemRouteProvider lookup inside a current-thread Tokio runtime panicked at the nested block_on.</method>
        <reference ref="tokio-runtime" />
        <precondition>The synchronous route API must be invoked on a thread currently executing a Tokio runtime.</precondition>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>A normal public API composition on Linux can panic instead of returning a recoverable error.</severity_rationale>
      <description>The native-route adapter creates a new current-thread Tokio runtime and calls Runtime::block_on for each synchronous netlink operation. Calling this path from a thread already executing a Tokio task can trigger Tokio's nested-runtime/block_on panic.</description>
      <impact>A public synchronous route lookup used from otherwise normal asynchronous application code can panic the process rather than returning a recoverable routing error.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Provide an async route-provider path and await the netlink future directly.</step>
        <step>For a synchronous API, delegate to a dedicated OS thread or a persistent worker/runtime rather than nesting block_on.</step>
        <step>Detect runtime context only as a fallback; do not rely on creating a second runtime on the same executor thread.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Call the synchronous route API from a Tokio test/task and assert it returns without panic.</test>
        <test>Exercise repeated concurrent lookups to verify worker/runtime lifecycle behavior.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-017" status="fixed" severity="medium" category="windows-routing">
      <title>Windows collapses distinct IPv4 and IPv6 adapter indices into one InterfaceId index</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="4" finding="PC-05" reported_severity="medium" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/net/platform/windows.rs:147-165,188-217,248-269</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that enumeration prefers IfIndex, discards Ipv6IfIndex, and later supplies the single stored value to constrained route lookup for either family.</method>
        <reference ref="microsoft-adapters" />
        <reference ref="microsoft-getbestroute2" />
        <precondition>The affected adapter must expose different IPv4 and IPv6 interface indices.</precondition>
        <limitation>The Windows-native routing failure was not reproduced locally.</limitation>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>This breaks supported family-constrained IPv6 routing on valid Windows adapter configurations.</severity_rationale>
      <description>Windows adapters expose both IfIndex and Ipv6IfIndex, and the two can differ. Enumeration stores only one value, preferring the IPv4 index when present. Constrained route lookup then passes this single index to GetBestRoute2 regardless of destination family.</description>
      <impact>IPv6 route selection constrained to an adapter can fail, select the wrong interface, or report inconsistent identity when that adapter's IPv4 and IPv6 indices differ.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Preserve adapter LUID and both family-specific indices internally.</step>
        <step>Use the destination or source family to select the proper index for GetBestRoute2.</step>
        <step>Match returned routes by LUID where possible and expose a stable portable identity separately from family-specific indices.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Use a synthetic adapter record with different IPv4 and IPv6 indices and verify constrained routing uses the correct one.</test>
        <test>Cover returned-route normalization for both families.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-018" status="fixed" severity="medium" category="feature-gating-ci">
      <title>The default Windows feature profile lacks documented interface enumeration and is not tested</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="1" finding="10" reported_severity="medium" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>Cargo.toml:13-36</location>
        <location>src/net/platform/mod.rs:145-155</location>
        <location>docs/README.md:3-20</location>
        <location>.github/workflows/ci.yml:24-32</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed the Windows dependency cfg, default feature set, unsupported default branch, documentation contract, and CI commands that select different branches.</method>
        <precondition>The package is built on Windows with default features rather than all features or no default features.</precondition>
        <limitation>The unsupported default-profile call was not executed on Windows.</limitation>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>The default supported Windows profile contradicts its documented capability and the configured CI matrix systematically misses that exact branch.</severity_rationale>
      <description>The default feature set enables live, but the portable pnet dependency is excluded on Windows. With default features and without native-route, system_interfaces returns Unsupported even though the documentation describes default/system interface enumeration. CI checks no-default-features and all-features; on Windows those select the no-live and native-route branches, respectively, so the actual default live-and-not-native-route branch is masked.</description>
      <impact>A default Windows build advertises a capability it cannot perform, and regressions in the default cfg path can remain invisible to the current feature matrix.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Implement Windows enumeration in the default live profile, or make defaults and documentation explicitly platform-specific.</step>
        <step>Run cargo check --locked --all-targets with default features on every CI platform.</step>
        <step>Compile supported minimal combinations independently, including live, native-route, native-layer2, and native-layer3.</step>
        <step>Consider a feature-powerset tool for compilation coverage.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Add a Windows default-feature smoke test for system_interfaces.</test>
        <test>Keep all-features tests but do not use them as a substitute for default and minimal profiles.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-019" status="fixed" severity="low" category="dns-protocol">
      <title>The public DNS decoder discards EDNS extended response codes</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="2" finding="5" reported_severity="medium" disposition="accepted-with-correction" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/workflow/dns/wire.rs:44-68,95-104,143-145,175,204-206,228,363-400,519-522,680-717</location>
        <location>src/workflow/dns/model.rs:331-350,386</location>
        <location>schemas/packetcraftr.output.v1.schema.json:1014-1018,1637-1641,2632-2636</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that the public complete-response decoder treats OPT generically, retains only the header's low four RCODE bits, and feeds a model and output schema that exclude values above 15. The built-in encoder sets the additional-record count to zero and emits no OPT.</method>
        <method type="runtime-reproduction">Direct public-decoder use on a complete BADVERS response with OPT extended RCODE 1 produced response_code 0 and no_error.</method>
        <reference ref="rfc6891" />
        <precondition>The response must use an EDNS extended RCODE and come from direct decoder use with an externally generated EDNS query, a noncompliant responder, or future built-in EDNS support. The current built-in encoder does not emit OPT, and RFC 6891 prohibits a compliant responder from including OPT when the request lacks it.</precondition>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>The public decoder and serialized contract misrepresent externally supplied EDNS errors, but compliant responses to the current built-in non-EDNS query path cannot trigger the defect.</severity_rationale>
      <description>OPT resource records (type 41) fall through to the generic unknown-record representation. The public decoder extracts only the four response-code bits in the DNS header, while EDNS stores the upper eight bits in the OPT TTL field. The response-code model is u8 and all three corresponding output-schema fields cap it at 15, so the full 12-bit space cannot be represented. BADVERS (16), for example, is emitted as response_code=0 and labeled no_error. The built-in query encoder always writes an additional-record count of zero and does not emit OPT.</description>
      <impact>Direct decoder use on standards-compliant responses to externally generated EDNS queries can misreport errors, causing incorrect diagnostics. Ordinary responses to the current built-in query encoder are unaffected when responders comply with RFC 6891.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Parse OPT as a dedicated pseudo-record and require the root owner name.</step>
        <step>Extract extended RCODE, EDNS version, flags, UDP payload size, and options.</step>
        <step>Combine full_rcode = (extended_rcode &lt;&lt; 4) | header_rcode.</step>
        <step>Widen the model to u16 and update schema maxima to 4095.</step>
        <step>Define handling for duplicate OPT records, malformed records, and unsupported EDNS versions.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Exercise direct decoder use with BADVERS and a zero header nibble.</test>
        <test>Exercise direct decoder use with a nonzero low nibble combined with nonzero extended bits.</test>
        <test>No OPT, duplicate OPT, malformed OPT, and unsupported-version fixtures.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-020" status="fixed" severity="low" category="dns-protocol">
      <title>DNS wire labels are incorrectly restricted to printable ASCII without dot bytes</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="2" finding="7" reported_severity="low-medium" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/workflow/dns/wire.rs:270-360,346-358</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed ASCII-graphic and no-dot validation in the length-delimited wire-label decoder and a String model without a lossless arbitrary-octet representation.</method>
        <method type="runtime-reproduction">A response with an embedded dot octet in an answer-owner label returned InvalidLabelData.</method>
        <reference ref="rfc1035" />
        <precondition>A response name must contain a legal wire octet that requires presentation escaping or is outside printable ASCII.</precondition>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>This is a standards-interoperability defect affecting unusual but valid DNS names, with limited broader impact.</severity_rationale>
      <description>The DNS decoder rejects label bytes that are not ASCII graphic characters and rejects a literal dot byte. Those are presentation-format constraints, not wire-format constraints: labels are length-delimited octet strings, and dot is only a separator in text form. The String-based name model cannot represent arbitrary octet labels losslessly without a defined escaping layer.</description>
      <impact>Structurally valid DNS responses can be rejected when an owner name or name-valued RDATA contains an embedded dot, NUL, non-ASCII octet, or another byte requiring presentation escaping.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Represent decoded names losslessly as byte labels or a dedicated DnsName type.</step>
        <step>Implement comparison by folding only ASCII A through Z where DNS case-insensitivity applies.</step>
        <step>Escape dot, backslash, and non-printable bytes only during presentation rendering.</step>
        <step>Allow the query-facing API to retain stricter hostname-like validation independently of response decoding.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Decode labels containing dot, NUL, high-bit bytes, and backslash without conflation and render them with defined escaping.</test>
        <test>Verify ASCII-only case-insensitive comparison without altering other octets.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-021" status="fixed" severity="medium" category="packet-model">
      <title>Removing the exact padding boundary silently changes protocol coverage semantics</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="1" finding="8" reported_severity="medium" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/packet/layer.rs:196-216</location>
        <location>src/packet/packet.rs:236-245</location>
        <location>src/protocol/common.rs:380-414</location>
        <location>src/client/internal/helpers.rs:71-102</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that removing the exact outside_layer index changes it to None, whose downstream interpretation excludes padding from every dependent payload.</method>
        <method type="runtime-reproduction">Removing the inner IPv4 boundary changed the enclosing IPv4 total length by the exact four-byte trailer size compared with retaining the shifted successor boundary.</method>
        <precondition>A packet must remove the exact boundary layer while a shifted successor should remain the first layer excluding the trailer.</precondition>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>The mutation can silently change emitted lengths, checksums, MTU calculations, and exact packet bytes in a supported packet-model operation.</severity_rationale>
      <description>Padding::outside_layer identifies the first layer whose declared length excludes the trailer. When removing the layer at exactly that index, the implementation sets the boundary to None. None means the padding is excluded from every dependent payload, not merely that the original boundary layer disappeared. If a successor layer shifts into the same position, it may still be the correct first excluding boundary.</description>
      <impact>Nested encapsulations can silently change outer protocol lengths, checksums, MTU calculations, and rebuilt bytes when a boundary layer is removed.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Preserve Some(index) when an appropriate successor remains at the shifted position.</step>
        <step>Otherwise require the caller to explicitly reassign or remove the coverage boundary.</step>
        <step>Do not silently reinterpret a protocol-relative trailer as link padding.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Construct Ethernet, outer IPv4, inner IPv4, UDP, raw payload, and padding with outside_layer at the inner IPv4.</test>
        <test>Remove the exact boundary and verify outer length/checksum coverage remains unchanged when UDP becomes the successor boundary.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-022" status="fixed" severity="low" category="api-contract">
      <title>Packet::structurally_eq is not symmetric for public Layer implementations</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="1" finding="9" reported_severity="medium" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/packet/packet.rs:207-220</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that structurally_eq compares matching protocol IDs and only fields exposed by the left-hand schema.</method>
        <method type="runtime-reproduction">Public custom layers with one shared ProtocolId and different schemas compared true in one direction and false in the other.</method>
        <precondition>Two public external Layer implementations must share a ProtocolId while exposing different schemas.</precondition>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>The method violates equality symmetry, but the failure requires custom layer implementations with an unusual shared-identifier/schema mismatch.</severity_rationale>
      <description>The function verifies matching protocol IDs and then iterates only the left layer's schema. Because Layer is publicly implementable, two layer types can share a ProtocolId while exposing different field schemas. Extra fields on the right are ignored, so a.structurally_eq(b) can be true while b.structurally_eq(a) is false.</description>
      <impact>The method violates the expected equality contract and can produce inconsistent assertions, deduplication, cache behavior, or change detection.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Compare schemas first, including field names and kinds in a canonical order.</step>
        <step>Alternatively compare the union of both field sets and require identical presence and values.</step>
        <step>Document whether layer implementation type also participates in structural identity.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Create two external Layer implementations with the same ProtocolId and different extra fields.</test>
        <test>Assert symmetry, reflexivity, and expected transitivity cases.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-023" status="fixed" severity="low" category="registry-api">
      <title>Rebinding a registry child with a different priority silently ignores the new priority</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="1" finding="11" reported_severity="lower severity" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/packet/registry.rs:382-408</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that duplicate detection checks only child identity, returns success, and leaves the earlier priority unchanged.</method>
        <precondition>A caller must rebind the same parent, discriminator, and child with a different priority.</precondition>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>This is a narrow, silent public-API configuration inconsistency that does not corrupt wire input or cross a safety boundary.</severity_rationale>
      <description>Binding the same parent, discriminator, and child again returns success whenever the child is already present, regardless of whether the requested priority differs. Priority affects binding order and reverse discriminator selection, so the successful call does not reflect the resulting state.</description>
      <impact>Callers that repeat a binding with a changed priority receive Ok although the earlier priority remains in effect, making composed-module ordering opaque and order-dependent.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Treat only an exact child-and-priority duplicate as idempotent.</step>
        <step>For the same child with a different priority, update deterministically or return a dedicated conflict error.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Bind the same child twice with equal priority and verify idempotence.</test>
        <test>Bind it with a different priority and verify either the documented update or explicit error.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-024" status="fixed" severity="low" category="neighbor-discovery">
      <title>A matching ARP/NDP frame can arrive before the request send and still satisfy discovery</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="4" finding="PC-10" reported_severity="low" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/net/neighbor/provider.rs:233-261</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed a freshness gap between the final pre-request drain and send, followed by matching that is not tied to the send instant.</method>
        <precondition>A matching unsolicited or stale ARP/NDP frame must arrive in the narrow drain-to-send race.</precondition>
        <limitation>The timing race was not reproduced with a native capture backend.</limitation>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>The lookup can accept evidence that did not answer its request, but only in a narrow local-network race.</severity_rationale>
      <description>Neighbor discovery drains frames captured before the request, then constructs and sends the ARP or NDP request. A matching frame can arrive in the race between the final pre-request drain and the actual send. Subsequent matching has no capture-timestamp or monotonic freshness check tied to the send event.</description>
      <impact>Stale, unsolicited, or unrelated neighbor traffic can satisfy the lookup even though it was not a response to the transmitted request.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Attach a monotonic received_at value to captured frames and require matched evidence to be at or after the attempt's send Instant.</step>
        <step>Alternatively tag capture generations around the send boundary so frames already queued cannot satisfy the new attempt.</step>
        <step>Retain pre-request frames as evidence only, as intended.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Inject a matching frame after the drain returns empty but before send completes; assert it cannot satisfy the request.</test>
        <test>Verify a matching frame received after send is accepted.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-025" status="fixed" severity="low" category="cli-parsing">
      <title>Parse-error output-mode detection ignores end-of-options semantics</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="3" finding="8" reported_severity="low" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/cli/errors.rs:105-119</location>
        <location>src/cli/runtime.rs:13-41</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that fallback scanning continues after the first end-of-options marker.</method>
        <method type="runtime-reproduction">target/debug/packetcraftr read -- --output=json extra exited 2 and emitted JSON.</method>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>This affects only parse-error presentation and does not alter successful command interpretation or packet behavior.</severity_rationale>
      <description>When Clap parsing fails, the fallback scans raw argv for output-mode flags but does not stop at the first '--'. An argument such as '--output=json' after '--' is positional data, yet the fallback treats it as an option and changes the format of the parse error.</description>
      <impact>The CLI can emit JSON instead of normal stderr formatting based on a positional filename or other post-terminator value.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Stop fallback option scanning at the first '--'.</step>
        <step>Prefer preserving output context from the primary parser instead of reparsing raw argv.</step>
        <step>If a fallback parser remains, make it observe option arity and position.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Run 'packetcraftr read -- --output=json extra' and assert normal parse-error formatting.</test>
        <test>Verify an actual pre-terminator --output=json still selects JSON error output.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-026" status="fixed" severity="low" category="fuzz-validation">
      <title>Fuzz case-range validation has an off-by-one overflow check</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="4" finding="PC-11" reported_severity="low" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/workflow/fuzz/model.rs:217</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that validation adds cases rather than cases minus one before the generation range is used.</method>
        <method type="runtime-reproduction">FuzzRequest::validate returned CaseIndexOverflow for first_case=u64::MAX and cases=1.</method>
        <precondition>The requested final valid case range must touch u64::MAX.</precondition>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>This rejects a representable but extremely narrow edge case without affecting ordinary fuzz ranges.</severity_rationale>
      <description>Validation checks first_case + cases for overflow, but a batch of cases occupies indices from first_case through first_case + cases - 1. Consequently, first_case=u64::MAX and cases=1 is rejected even though the single generated index is representable.</description>
      <impact>A valid edge-case reproduction request cannot be expressed at the maximum case index.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Validate first_case + (cases - 1) after cases has been proven nonzero.</step>
        <step>Handle usize-to-u64 conversion explicitly on platforms where needed.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Accept (u64::MAX, 1).</test>
        <test>Reject (u64::MAX, 2) and other truly overflowing ranges.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-027" status="fixed" severity="low" category="replay-timing">
      <title>Extremely small positive replay delays can round to zero and silently become immediate</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="4" finding="PC-12" reported_severity="low" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/workflow/replay/model.rs:45-54</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that finite positive timing values are accepted without rejecting a derived zero Duration.</method>
        <method type="runtime-reproduction">Rust 1.96.0 returned Ok(0ns) for positive inputs 4.9e-10, 1e-20, and 1/f64::MAX.</method>
        <reference ref="rust-duration" />
        <precondition>A configured rate or scale must derive an interval below Duration's representable nanosecond resolution.</precondition>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>This silently changes an extreme positive pacing request into immediate replay but affects only sub-nanosecond inputs.</severity_rationale>
      <description>Scaled and fixed-rate timing accept any finite positive value, then convert the derived seconds to Duration. Values below representable nanosecond resolution can produce Duration::ZERO even though the selected mode is paced rather than immediate.</description>
      <impact>A caller requesting positive pacing can receive burst/immediate transmission without an error, altering traffic shape and potentially invalidating rate assumptions.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>For non-immediate modes, reject a derived zero duration as unrepresentable.</step>
        <step>Alternatively clamp to a documented minimum positive duration such as one nanosecond.</step>
        <step>Apply the rule consistently to scaled original intervals and fixed-rate periods.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Use a very high fixed rate and a very small positive scale factor and verify explicit rejection or documented clamping.</test>
        <test>Verify Immediate remains the only mode that intentionally returns zero.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-028" status="fixed" severity="low" category="capture-statistics">
      <title>Npcap drop aggregation aliases when an interval contains at least 2^32 combined drops</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="4" finding="PC-13" reported_severity="low" disposition="accepted-with-correction" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>src/net/platform/npcap.rs:411-412</location>
        <location>src/net/platform/live_capture.rs:360-369</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that two u32 counters are wrapping-added before a later wrapping subtraction.</method>
        <source_correction>Modulo arithmetic preserves the combined delta when total component increments between samples are below 2^32, including an individual component wrap. Information is lost only when the summed interval delta reaches or exceeds 2^32.</source_correction>
        <precondition>At least 2^32 combined dropped and network-dropped events must accrue between two statistics samples.</precondition>
        <limitation>The required Npcap loss volume was not reproduced on Windows.</limitation>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>The premature aggregation can lose a 2^32 increment even when both component deltas are individually recoverable, but only after an extreme loss burst or sampling gap.</severity_rationale>
      <description>Npcap reports dropped and network_dropped separately, but the adapter combines them with wrapping_add into one u32 counter before the generic capture layer computes a wrapping delta. The identity delta((a+b) mod 2^32) = (delta(a)+delta(b)) mod 2^32 means individual component wraps are handled correctly while the summed increments remain below 2^32. If each component advances by less than 2^32 but their recoverable deltas sum to at least that modulus, the pre-summed value aliases and loses exactly one 2^32 increment. Multiple wraps within either component are independently unobservable from two u32 samples and are outside this narrower defect.</description>
      <impact>Receiver loss can be undercounted by 2^32 after an extreme loss interval even when both individual counter deltas remain recoverable, weakening operational diagnostics and overflow evidence.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Carry each native counter separately through the abstraction.</step>
        <step>Compute the wrapping delta of each component independently and sum the widened deltas afterward.</step>
        <step>Use wider accumulated totals for exported statistics.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Simulate one component wrapping while the combined interval increment remains below 2^32 and verify that the current modulo result is exact.</test>
        <test>Simulate combined increments equal to and greater than 2^32 and verify that separate widened deltas retain the full total.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
    <issue id="BR-029" status="fixed" severity="informational" category="supply-chain-ci">
      <title>The committed CI workflow has no advisory, source, or license policy gate</title>
      <source_findings>
        <source response="4" finding="PC-14" reported_severity="informational" />
      </source_findings>
      <locations>
        <location>.github/workflows/ci.yml:24-32</location>
        <location>Cargo.lock:474-475</location>
      </locations>
      <verification>
        <method type="static-code-trace">Confirmed that the CI workflow contains formatting, checking, Clippy, and tests but no advisory, source, or license policy job, and that Cargo.lock contains paste 1.0.15 transitively.</method>
        <reference ref="rustsec-2024-0436" />
        <limitation>Advisory state is time-dependent and is recorded as of the audit date.</limitation>
      </verification>
      <severity_rationale>This is a verified preventive-control and maintenance gap, not a demonstrated vulnerability in packetcraftr.</severity_rationale>
      <description>The CI workflow runs formatting, checking, Clippy, and tests but no dependency advisory, source, or license policy gate. One input report specifically identified the locked transitive dependency paste 1.0.15 as an unmaintained-package maintenance exposure under RUSTSEC-2024-0436. This item is not a demonstrated vulnerability and advisory status should be revalidated when remediating.</description>
      <impact>Dependency maintenance or policy regressions can enter the lockfile without an automated signal.</impact>
      <remediation>
        <step>Add an advisory and policy tool such as cargo-deny, cargo-audit, or an equivalent maintained gate.</step>
        <step>Define explicit policy for unmaintained advisories, permitted sources, licenses, and reviewed exceptions.</step>
        <step>Upgrade, replace, or consciously document the transitive dependency when feasible.</step>
      </remediation>
      <regression_tests>
        <test>Make the CI gate operate on Cargo.lock and fail on an unapproved advisory or disallowed source/license.</test>
        <test>Keep exceptions narrow, versioned, and time-bounded.</test>
      </regression_tests>
    </issue>
  </issues>
</bugreport>
